# **Benjamin Cato**

With over a decade of experience in **front-end development**, I thrive on infusing projects with creativity and passion. I excel in collaborative environments and approach each project as a work of art, taking pride in my role as the artist.

402 Bridgepoint Ln.
Woodstock, GA 30189
(404) 374-1696
bcato3000@gmail.com
bcato3000.github.io/portfolio

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Whereoware, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

May 2023 - October 2023

Expertise in creating modular components via React and Storybook, employing MVC architecture, and optimizing user interfaces for Optimizely (CMS).

### **Perficient**, Alpharetta — *Lead front-end developer*

December 2021 - May 2023

Created SPAs via React for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore/Optimizely), modular components, and applications.

# **Fleetcor**, Atlanta — Senior front-end developer

August 2020 - December 2021

Collaborated with UI/UX designers and bridged the gap between graphical representations and technical implementation.

# **BrainJocks / Perficient**, Alpharetta — Lead front-end developer

April 2013 - July 2020

HTML5, CSS3, Sass, LESS and Javascript. Development for large-scale CMS platforms (Sitecore/EPI), modular/reusable components.

#### **EDUCATION**

**The Creative Circus**, Atlanta — *Interactive Development* 

Graduate: 2012 - 2013

**Chattahoochee Tech**, Acworth — Computer Science

Graduate 2001 - 2003

**Kennesaw State University,** Kennesaw — Computer Science

1997 - 2000

#### **SKILLS**

HTML5

CSS<sub>3</sub>

Sass

JavaScript

**TypeScript** 

Storybook

**RESTful APIs** 

SPAs (React/Vue)

Node

Web components

Responsive design/dev

Cross-browser

Accessibility standards

Git

UX

Adobe creative suite

Figma

Agile/Scrum

Client-facing contributor

PC Windows

Mac iOS